Have you ever dreamt about the future of sustainable cement production?
And it occupies your mind, whatever you do.
Not giving you a rest, even if you just want to relax.
So I did, what everybody would have done in my place.
Call my favourite fortune teller.
Hello, I'm sorry, but do you know how we can reach Paris Agreement compatible cement production?
Don't worry dear, you talk to a true fortune teller.
Nothing can hide from my third eye.
It's cement, we're talking about.
Yes, thank you.
Cement is currently responsible for 8% of the global greenhouse gas emissions.
So it's really important to better understand how to decarbonise it.
What a concrete problem!
I'm connecting with the universe right now.
But wait, there's an obscure fog clouding my vision...
It seems that cement is not only hard to abate, but also hard to predict
Hmm, before, she never failed me.
You know, if you try attending the ISIE conference,
there's a poster by Amelie Müller and colleagues on prospective life cycle assessment of the global cement production.
They coupled the output of intergrated assessment models with prospective LCA
and that could shed light into those fogs that my crystal ball cannot unveil.
Their work shows that decarbonising  the cement industry requires significant amounts of carbon capture and storage infrastructure
and should include measures beyond a change of production technologies.
More you can find at the Industrial Ecology conference in Leiden.
Yes!!! Thanks!!!
There was just what I was looking for. Fantastic.
Byeeeeee
Hmm, maybe I should look more into scientific future scenarios as well.
Let's change the cars. Let's think for a while.
Supply can wait, the raw materials from mines? Hoping for the best, but expecting the worst.
Are they gonna be ready or not?
From find to mine can't take forever. No one could tell who won't go never.
Individual, mines which, decisions can't switch, we'll need to have a plan.
Can you imagine when this race is won?
Mines will be ready to supply million tons.
Simulating our mines we're getting in tune. We'll need to have a plan.
Forever lithium.... we will need to have more mines
Do you really think they last forever? Forever? Or never?
Do you really think they last forever? Forever?
Some are like water, some are like rocks, some will be ready, and some will be not.
So much uncertainty how this can be done.
What makes them go wrong?
Geology, costs and price also counts
From east or west, or north from the south
Monte Carlo does a 1000 runs
And we forcast however
So many opportunities couldn't happen today
Circular economy still needs to play
So many things are swinging out the blue. We let them come true.
Forever lithium, we will need to have more mines.
Do you really think they last forever? Forever? Or never?
Do you really think they last forever? Or never? Forever?
Forever lithium, we will need to have more mines.
If we want to supply happily, forever....
North Rhine Westfalia is an important industrial hub for the steel sector in Germany.
40% of the German steel production is yielded here in the Ruhrgebiet.
The existing blast furnace production process is a very
carbon-intensive as it depends on coal to reduce the iron ore.
Therefore, the industry is undergoing a transformation
process to shift to hydrogen-based steel.
Nonetheless, extensive amounts of renewable energies
are needed to secure the green hydrogen demand.
Also, such a transformation is associated with significant alterations
in terms of processes and infrastructure and raw materials.
Hence, the study aims at presenting an approach to analyse and quantify these changes.
Construction is a material-intensive industry.
Using recycled aggregates in the state of natural
ones is a promising circular economy application.
In this regard, various aspects and parameters
have to be considered. First, the type
of materials. Second, location as it affects the transportation and total costs.
The third dimension is time. For example, the
German Federal State of North Rhine Westphalia,
which is the region of interest in our analysis, was extremely destroyed in the Second World War.
Therefore, the housing stock in each district is different.
For example, the housing stocks in some
regions have high ratios of classic houses,
while other have higher proportions of modern buildings.
The different housing stocks imply dissimilar
construction and demolition activities in terms of time.
The different building generations also imply dissimilar
compositions and consequently material outflows.
The demographic change also has a significant impact on the housing demand.
For example, while the urban centers attract more
inhabitants, the population of other regions is declining.
Therefore, the dynamic locational material flow analysis has
been derived to integrate all of these parameters in one model.
The world needs increasingly more electricity, but all energy production
impacts our climate and biodiversity during construction and operation.
Balancing energy needs and environmental impacts
is the aim of this game that we developed at NTSU.
On an island, with mountains, forests, meadows
and rivers, a city needs efficient electricity.
Biodeiversity is found in all regions but
have species with different levels of threat.
With carbon points, you can buy power infrastructures such as
hydro, wind, solar and fossil power plants and power lines.
All have a different carbon impact during construction and
operation and produce a different amount of electricity.
Your job is now to build and place the required power
infrastructure for the city with the least biodiversity impacts.
But you only have 5 rounds and a limited
carbon budget to achieve this goal.
Good luck in solving the energy and environmental crisis.