Have you ever dreamt about the future of sustainable cement production?
It occupies your mind, whatever you do,
not giving you a rest, even if you just want to relax.
So I did what everybody would have done in my place.
Call inta my favourite fortune teller.
Hello, I'm sorry, but do you know how we can reach
Paris Agreement compatible cement production?
Don't worry dear, you talk to a true fortune teller.
Nothing can hide from my third eye.
It's cement, we're talking about.
Yes, thank you.
Cement is currently responsible for 8% of the global greenhouse gas emissions.
So it's really important to better understand how to decarbonize it.
What a concrete problem.
I'm connecting with the universe right now.
But wait, there's an obscure fog clouding my vision
It seems that cement is not only hard to abate, but also has predict.
Hmm, before she never failed me.
You know, if you try attending the ISIE conference, there's a poster by Amelie Müller
and colleagues on prospective lifecycle assessment of the global cement production.
They coupled the output of ultra-calibre assessment models with prospective LCA,
and that could shed light into those fogs that my crystal ball cannot amaze.
Their work shows that decarbonizing cement industry requires significant amounts of carbon
capture and storage infrastructure and should include measures beyond a change of production technologies.
More you can find at the Industrial Ecology conference in Leiden.
Yes, thanks.
There was just what I was looking for.
Fantastic.
I should look more into the scientific future scenarios as well.
Thank you.